## **Kyle Romero**

kgromero@gmail.com (281) 857-9006 https://kgromero.com

Hello! My name is Kyle Romero. I am a software development manager, with full-stack technical lead experience, living in Jersey City, NJ. I have a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering from Texas Tech University, and have worked in the IT field since 2007 focused on internal software development. Currently, I am a manager of operations technology, and previously was a team lead and senior developer at Worldwide Machinery, and a technical lead at HP. I have extensive knowledge of all aspects of a successful software project, and have used many different technologies and methodologies over the years.

**Linkedin** kyleromero **Github** romero927

## **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES	C#, ASP.NET (WebForms / MVC), Typescript, ES6, Python
DATABASES	MS-SQL
SCRIPTING	Bash, Powershell (Novice)
FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES	.NET (2.0 to 4.8), .NET Core 3.x, ASP.NET MVC WebAPI, Angular, React, Gatsby, Redux, Webpack, SASS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Azure Cognitive Services, Azure Logic App
DEVELOPMENT TOOLS	Azure DevOps, Github, SVN (TortoiseSVN), Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SSMS, Slack (Notifications), Sharepoint Online, JIRA, Trello, Windows 10, Linux (Ubuntu), MacOS Sierra, IIS, Kestrel (Novice), Node + NPM / YARN + Express + PM2, NGINX Reverse Proxy, Docker (Novice), Azure, Netlify, Digital Ocean, LucidCharts, Visio, SSRS, PowerBI
FORMER PROFICIENCIES	C++

## **EXPERIENCE**

# InfraSource, A Quanta Services Company (part of MEARS Group) Operations Technology Manager Oct 2017 - Present

Construction and Professional Services (Natural Gas, Oil, and Electric Power Industry)

- Direct-Report to CIO of MEARS Group, helping to define and drive software development strategy
- Architect and explore new technology solutions (focused on digital transformation)
- Build out company's internal tools using appropriate technologies
- Manage a team of internal and external developers and project managers
- Coordinate external and internal teams using Agile processes
- Travel as needed to various sites around US to deploy new software solutions and manage IT relationship with other groups

- Interface between technical and non-technical personnel; help to bridge the communication gap
- Provide consultation on software development initiatives across MEARS Group
- Create learning curriculum for new developers and provide training / KT sessions
- Manage DevOps, CICD, and PM processes
- Administration of various systems including: Windows Servers, Azure, Azure DevOps, and Sharepoint Online
- Prototyping / hands-on exploration of new technologies

## **Worldwide Machinery**

**Team Lead / Senior Software Developer** Apr 2016 - Oct 2017

Heavy Machinery Rental and Sales Company

- Manage project workflow using Agile Scrum methodology
- Manage junior developers' workloads
- Develop modern ASP.NET MVC WebAPI
- Develop modern Mobile-first Web Application using React, Redux, Typescript (ES6), Node.js + Express + NPM, Babel, Webpack, and SASS
- Maintain legacy ERP application using .NET Winforms (C#, MS SQL)
- Implement and Maintain Project and DevOps Processes using: JIRA, Bitbucket (GIT), TeamCity, Trello,
   Slack, Lucidcharts
- Proactively identify process improvements, as well as project opportunities
- Maintain / troubleshoot hardware infrastructure as needed (Windows / Ubuntu Servers)

## HP Inc.

Technical Lead (IT Developer / Engineer III) Dec 2013 - Feb 2016

**Consumer IT Products** 

- Led development team working on enterprise level product quality / escalation management tool.
- Helped manage both onshore and offshore, full time and contingent developers.
- Helped to define and improve processes used on project, including development of a customized disciplined agile methodology and setting project timelines.
- Administered Team Foundation Server (source and requirements).
- Managed quality control and workloads for developers on project.
- Managed release process for tool.
- Worked with business to define requirements and develop architecture for project.
- Familiar with all aspects of project, from both technical and business standpoints.
- While working on .NET Applications, received exposure to Big Data technologies, such as Hadoop and HP Vertica, as well as Dashboarding Technologies, such as Qlikview and Tableau.
- During the year 2015, led team to successfully complete clone of our systems to be used on both sides of HP after the company split into two.

#### HP

Software Developer (IT Developer / Engineer II) Nov 2011 - Dec 2013

- Worked on ASP.NET Web applications incorporating a 3-Tier approach.
- Did work on all three tiers (MS SQL Database, VB.NET Middle tier object libraries, and ASP.NET + jQueryUI frontend).

- Project was managed using Agile Scrum methodology (Received Certified Scrum Master certification 2012).
- Source control system was Team Foundation Server.

## X-Fab Texas, Inc.

Software / Systems Engineer Dec 2009 - Nov 2011

Pure-play Semiconductor Foundry

- Development of ASP.NET/C# Web applications to serve as frontends for MSSQL databases.
- Developed .NET Web / Console / Winforms Applications.
- Involved in Database Design. Administered Windows and Linux servers.
- Designed Shell / Batch scripts. Developed C++ console applications.
- Deployed machine monitoring system. Developed Inventory tracking system.
- Deployed Documentation system to sites globally.

## X-Fab Texas, Inc.

IT Intern May 2007 - Dec 2009

Internship between TTU EE Department and X-Fab, Texas

 Developed various internal software projects, including statistical analysis programs, format conversion software, and .NET web applications.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Texas Tech University**

Aug 2005 - Dec 2009

Bachelor of Science - Computer Engineering GPA:

2.944

## **REFERENCES**

— Available Upon Request